<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Naim&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Naim&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stop Malware Using Macros: Windows Sandbox</title>
      <link>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/stop-malware-using-macros-windows-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/stop-malware-using-macros-windows-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>Malware continues to be a major threat to individuals and organizations alike. One common way that malware is delivered is through the use of malicious macros in office products, which are often spread through social engineering tactics. While sandboxing office products could potentially mitigate this issue, it&amp;rsquo;s not a simple solution. This is because sandboxing would not be backwards compatible, meaning it would break the existing workflow for many users and companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host Your Website on GitHub with Hugo: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/host-your-website-on-github-with-hugo-a-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/host-your-website-on-github-with-hugo-a-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through lot&amp;rsquo;s of pain to build my website (again) using Hugo for the 3rd time. 🙂 So I&amp;rsquo;m now documenting my process so that I can redo these in the future smoothly.
Prerequisite  Link to heading   I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you already know how to work with github for my own convenience. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, there are lots of great blogs and youtube videos just one google search away!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Wide Range of Projects Provided by abuse.ch</title>
      <link>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/exploring-the-wide-range-of-projects-provided-by-abuse.ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/exploring-the-wide-range-of-projects-provided-by-abuse.ch/</guid>
      <description>abuse.ch is providing community driven threat intelligence on cyber threats with a strong focus on malware and botnets. It is a collection of following projects:
MalwareBazaar  Link to heading   MalwareBazaar is a place where your can get malware samples which is shared by malware researchers for infosec community.
What it offers?
 Latest &amp;amp; Old malware samples.  Feodo Tracker  Link to heading   Feodo Tracker is place where you can get latest malicious botnet C2 servers IP associated with Emotet, Dridex, TrickBot, QakBot and BazarLoader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naimulislam9m.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>As-salamu alaykum wa-rahmatu-llahi wa-barakatuh.
This is my first blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll post here about my learning and thoughts. Hope you&amp;rsquo;ll find something useful here! 😄
See you again friend. ❤️</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
